HaxTalks Subs
Translations by MysteriousAura
Qiu Shan Jun and Xu You Rong will become husband and wife
Are there any objections?
I object!
Mister!
Take him down!
Everyone, come on!
Wait a second
If you have something to say, step up here and do it
Living all these seasons in the mountains, the wind and frost have dyed my clothes
From far away, the youth play
This red dust substance isn't like snow, it is like the moon
My clothes feel thin and cool, they mock and make me crazy
Asking what the meaning of my life is, or what I need to do
But the answer cannot be found in the books
Living a long life is hard
I hope I won't get lost along the way
Asking what the meaning of my life is, or what I need to do
But the answer cannot be found in the books
Living a long life is hard
I hope I won't get lost along the way
Way of Choices
Asking For Enlightenment
Emperor, I have heard that
Qiu Shan Jun and Xu You Rong will become husband and wife
You asked if anyone had an objection
So I said that I object
Who are you?
Who do you think you are? Why are you objecting?
I am engaged to Xu You Rong
She will become my wife in the future
Naturally, she can’t marry anyone else
Ridiculous!
Do you have no shame?
I had to come a long way to attend this, are you mocking me?
I've never heard that Xu You Rong was already engaged.
Where is your proof?
I have the marriage vow as evidence
This brat!
Even if you took out the Heavenly books to serve as proof,
no one here will believe you!
I believe him!
My master has the right to marry anyone
Hmph. I believe him as well. This guy sure is a feisty one
You should never be surprised by his decisions
He doesn’t need to prove that he will be her future husband
I'll still believe him if he says something even more ridiculous like being the son of the demon king.
After I left my home in the south,
I've gain the respect of tens of thousands of people
The Emperor himself asked me to take care of his family affairs
That year, the Emperor dubbed me as “The Master Who Has Ten Thousand Followers”
And so, even the Divine Empress respects me a great deal
I can’t believe that some little punk will dare insult me like this!
The rest of you shouldn’t even give these insignificant beings the time of day
Allow me to teach you two a lesson!
Hey old man. Just because you're old
doesn't mean you can bully us like this
Presumptuous!
Be careful.
This person has already stepped foot into another dimension and is too strong
Only the Empress or village chief Mao can match up to him
Stop this right now!
Hold on!
Watch out!
Mister Jin!
You are...
Jin Yu Lu!
Mhm. That’s correct
What in the world are you doing here?
Looks like General Jin has blessed us with his appearance
Please forgive us
Someone, please find a seat for General Jin
Emperor, you are too kind
There’s no need
Jin Yu Lu? Isn’t he one of the four legendary generals of the demon realm?
Umm, yes, Mister
Jin Yu Lu!? I only heard rumours about him actually existing!
What is a person of his caliber doing here??
Mister Jin has always been protecting me
Wait...what??? Then you..?
Master, I wasn’t trying to hide my identity on purpose
That’s not your fault, it’s just that there are many people who are curious about your identity
Do you want to tell us?
I will listen to my master, of course!
My last name is Bai. Bai as in Bai Di Castle
My mother is the Empress of the west
My father
Is Bai Xing Ye
And my master?
Chen Chang Sheng
I’ll ask again, old man. Are you still going to try and get rid of me?
Hmph! I don’t have time for that!
Everyone else, do we still need to object to my master and his wife to be’s marriage vow?
The famous Bai Di Castle: it is home for eight hundred miles of red soil
I am Gou Han Shi
I am Chen Chang Sheng
We all know that the mothers and fathers on both sides are set on the marriage
Now look at the marriage vow in your hands
The last half belongs to you, but the first half belongs to us
However
But what?
In retrospect, all of this isn’t important
That’s because the person who sets the marriage aren’t the parents, nor the person who wrote the marriage vow
It’s the people getting married that will make the final decision
Anyway, my brothers and I have already consulted Miss You Rong about this
So even if that marriage vow in your hands is authentic,
Will she really be willing to marry you?
If you really care about Miss You Rong, shouldn’t you respect her thoughts?
As a man, you need to know that
Right...if Xu You Rong wants to marry Qiu Shan Jun
Will a marriage vow prevent that so easily?
Also, Qiu Shan Jun is the Dragon, how can Chen Chang Sheng even compare to him?
That’s right!
How do you know that’s what Xu You Rong really desires?
Speaking all this nonsense
What’s the point?
Yeah, who cares about all that fancy stuff you just said?
In my eyes, passion is the key
Yup. Stop trying to give everyone silly ideas
But the wedding matter between Qiu Shan Jun and Xu You Rong
Is for the good of humanity! With their marriage, we can repel the demons!
Everyone wishes for their marriage to become a reality!
In order to repel the demons, everyone has to make sacrifices
Am I not correct?
May I ask, is this really the real problem at hand?
To repel the demon clan, to unite humanity
We need to force a girl to marry someone she doesn’t even want to marry?
What kind of logic is that?
If I must say everything now, my marriage with Xu You Rong is the actual matter we need to care about
None of you have the right to object
Miss You Rong is not here right now, so no one knows what she thinks about all of this
That been said, please forget everything I said,
I wasted both of our time
But the happenings tonight, rest assured that everyone has heard your opinion
My senior brother, however, is not here either,
so I don’t know what he thinks either
So I think this isn’t fair
How will it be fair, then?
As an apprentice of our master,
I have the right to represent him
As the younger brother of my senior brother,
I must not embarrass him either
So whatever the case,
I always have to do something
Now…
Please enlighten myself and the others
Is he serious? Will Orthodox Academy really have the nerve to fulfill that request?
On my way here, I got the news that Orthodox Academy has re-opened
That immediately made me very curious
as to what kind of person would do such a thing
Tonight, I now know that Miss Luo Luo also attends Orthodox Academy
And her teacher is an extraordinary person indeed
Tonight is the third night of Qing Tong Yan,
it’s also the last chance to enroll in a school
We came from so far away,
so we can’t pass up this opportunity
In that case, I ask Orthodox Academy to enlighten us
To fight or not to fight?
If you want, we will fight!
How about we discuss this?
If you don’t, Qiu Shan Jun will be hard pressed
and won't be able to let it go, I suggest you fight it out
It’s very late though, so make it quick
Looks like Qiu Shan Jun won’t be able to get a wife
Stop trying to find an excuse to kill Chen Chang Sheng
We’re only going to negotiate. Don’t overthink it
Hmph. What’s with all this leaving the mountain stuff? Seems like a lie to me
Do you have no shame?
You’re clearly just trying to find an excuse to kill us
Ridiculous!
Tang Tang. Back off now.
Don’t forget that you’re a student of Heavenly Academy
Who’s side are you on? Hmph.
Don’t try to use the name of Heavenly Academy to stop me
I once said that I wanted to beat Tian Hai Ya Er. Saying that much was enough for you to prevent me from attending Qing Tong Yan
Who cares if even the Tian Hai family is afraid of Heavenly Academy?
This isn’t the Heavenly Academy that I imagined it to be.
The so called best school.
Don’t ever try to use the name of that academy to stop me!
Shut it, right now!
The entrance exams are already over. If you leave the academy,
how are you going to enter the Grand Examination next year?
Your father has placed his trust in me. I definitely will not permit the trouble that you are trying to cause!
That’s my own business. It’s none of yours
You can come to my school. Students of Orthodox Academy have the right to enter the Grand Examination too
Okay. Let’s do that!
Luo Luo, tell caretaker to write his name on the registration documents later.
Don’t forget to get him to stamp it as well
Gladly. That means we have four students now!
What an outrage!
Congratulations. Orthodox Academy has another student now
Thank you very much
If my memory is correct, tonight is the third night of Qing Tong Yan.
That means it’s the night for the writing portion
Is that right?
Don’t be ridiculous
I beg your pardon?
This entire country knows that you are a master in Daoism
There's no way we can find someone as skilled as you are in that respect
You want to have a writing test? What’s the point?
I am just an ordinary person, I’m not a genius
The only thing I’m good at is straight reading
Reading is my xiu xing. Knowledge is my power
I’m using my own power to win. What part of that is ridiculous?
How are we even going to have a writing test?
Don’t tell me you want to produce the test papers right this instant?
Won’t fighting be much easier and efficient?
How about it?
No objections here
If you persist, I will agree to your proposal
You can decide the setting, and to person who will be fighting
Then, let’s head outside the palace to fight
After you
Letting us pick where we fight
and who will be fighting doesn’t really make a difference
They’re all the top seven students.
Winning against any one of them will be difficult
...so that’s why Gou Han Shi was so confident
He’s just like Qiu Shan Jun in the sense that he’s at a much higher level than us
Almost like a divine being
He brought up the written test so he won’t embarrass us if we fight him
He was being considerate
I brought up the fighting because I was hoping we would have a better chance at winning the best out of three with Luo Luo and myself fighting
You don't have to fight
As long as you don’t fight, they don’t have a way to recover their shame
Then you can continue forcing your marriage with Xu You Rong onto them
You’re saying like we can really win against them
Doesn’t matter, we need to fight anyway.
Princess Luo Luo, I will be fighting the seventh ranked student
Okay, Guan Fei Bai will be my opponent then
I am representing Orthodox Academy and will be fighting the first match.
I want to challenge the seventh ranked student!
Sure
Please, after you
Come and get it!
Three Forms of Wen Shui?!